# RAMRUP MAHATO

## **Software Developer**

E +91-9031937105 (whatsapp)

2nd cross, Marathahalli Colony Pin Code - 560037

☑ ramrupmahato1996@gmail.com

d https://ramrup- mahato.github.io/portfolio

SUMMARY

Founder, Designer & Developer of kizostudy.com. Experienced Software Developer with 3+ years of expertise in ReactJS, React Native, Next.js, MongoDB, ExpressJS, NodeJS, Git, and project management. Seeking opportunities to apply technical skills, learn new technologies, and deliver value. Strong problem-solving, communication, and collaboration skills.

## **TECH SKILLS**

React.js	React Native	JavaScript (ES6+)		Redux	HTML5/CS	SS3	ECMAScript		Next.js
Node.js	Express.js	MongoDb	Tailwind css		naterial UI	I UI Boots		Git	ImageKit.io
Socket.io	React Hooks	s TypeScrip	ot npm	/yarn	Context Al	PI			

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### 02/2024 - Present

Bangalore

#### Software Developer

**Deeporion Technology Pvt Ltd** 

- As a React Native Mobile Developer, responsible for designing, developing, and maintaining highquality mobile applications for both iOS and Android platforms.
- Collaborated with designers to translate wireframes, working closely with cross-functional teams to ensure seamless integration and functionality.
- · Created responsive pages using React Native, enhancing user interface and experience.
- · Conducted extensive UI testing for web and mobile applications, identifying and fixing bugs.
- · Troubleshot and resolved technical issues across web and mobile platforms.
- · Oversaw bug-fixing tasks for team members, ensuring timely resolution.
- Led the React team, improving project efficiency by 20%

#### 09/2021 - 12/2023

Bangalore

#### Frontend Developer

Artificial Mind & Intelligence Technology Pvt. Ltd.

- Spearheaded front-end development projects, implementing features to enhance website responsiveness and user experience.
- · Worked on multiple projects from scratch, ensuring seamless integration and functionality.
- Improved application performance by identifying and resolving database and front-end component issues.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to design and implement scalable solutions.
- Increased user engagement by 40% through optimized features and functionality.

#### 03/2021 - 08/2021

Bangalore

#### Intern

**Insphere Ideas Pvt Ltd** 

· learn and work as an intern in Insphere Ideas Pvt Ltd on Python.

## **EDUCATION**

Bangalore

Bachelor's degree in Electrical & Electronic (EEE) Engineering
AMC Engineering College

#### **PROJECTS**

## GolfCart (iOS US Client Project for Builder.ai)

Deeporion Technology Pvt Ltd

- Worked as a software expert to enhance the home page, navigation menu, advanced search, filter, and chats with instructors and players.
- · Utilized React Native for development.
- · Collaborated with a team to complete the project for an iOS US client.

#### TryDyota (E-commerce Website)

https://tridyota.com

Artificial Mind & Intelligence Technology Pvt. Ltd.

- · Led front-end modifications and oversaw features like registration, login, password management, and admin site.
- Utilized React.js (admin), Next.js (user side), React Native (iOS and Android), JavaScript, Tailwind CSS, Redux, Context API, React Hooks, HTML5, ECMAScript, Socket.io, ImageKit.io, Axios, push notifications.

## HomeScouts (E-commerce Website)

Artificial Mind & Intelligence Technology Pvt. Ltd.

- · Led front-end development; crafted features like Admin Control Panel and chat from scratch.
- Integrated RESTful APIs for data retrieval.
- Utilized React.js, Redux, Context API, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, Socket.io, Bootstrap, ImageKit, Axios, real-time chat, push notifications.

## Tunnel Management System (TMS)

Artificial Mind & Intelligence Technology Pvt. Ltd.

- · Developed a traffic control system with real-time accident alerts; integrated APIs for data retrieval and control.
- · Led front-end integration.
- Utilized React.js, JavaScript, React Hooks, Context API, HTML5, CSS3, Socket.io, ImageKit, Material UI, Visual Dashboard, real-time push notifications.

## personal project

kizostudy.com => https://kizostudy.com/about

Gharvilla => https://incomparable-cassata-b7db6b.netlify.app/

mini TV => https://singular-parfait-4abc8b.netlify.app/

portfolio => https://ramrup-mahato.github.io/portfolio/

#### LANGUAGES

English Hindi Nepali

## TRAINING / COURSES

Gen Y Analytica (machine Learning)

Internship in Machine Learning